[
    {
        "question": "Which city is home to the world`s largest hotel lobby?",
        "answer": "San Francisco -- The Hyatt Regency`s lobby spans 42,000 sq. ft. (a Guinness record) and features a 20-story atrium."
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is Kamchatca Peninsula, home to 29 active volcanoes?",
        "answer": "Russia -- The peninsula is part of the Ring of Fire, which stretches nearly 25,000 miles around the Pacific Ocean."
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the coldest town in the world?",
        "answer": "Oymyakon, Russia -- Located in Siberia, temperatures can reach minus 88 Fahrenheit. It`s so cold, planes cannot land there."
    },
    {
        "question": "How low is the lowest point of Death Valley?",
        "answer": "282 feet below sea level"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Columbia River flows into what body of water?",
        "answer": "Pacific Ocean"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the two letter abbreviation for Alaska?",
        "answer": "AK"
    },
    {
        "question": "The city of Muskogee is located in which US state?",
        "answer": "Oklahoma"
    },
    {
        "question": "What city is home to the headquarters of the Boeing Company?",
        "answer": "Chicago"
    },
    {
        "question": "What river is located along the southern border of Texas?",
        "answer": "Rio Grande River"
    },
    {
        "question": "Perth is the capital of which Australian state?",
        "answer": "Western Australia"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does the name Botswana mean?",
        "answer": "Land of the Tswana"
    },
    {
        "question": "What year did Botswana gain its independence from the United Kingdom?",
        "answer": "1966"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which U.S. city can you ride the Mud Island Monorail?",
        "answer": "Memphis, Tennessee"
    },
    {
        "question": "What European city hosts an annual wine-throwing festival?",
        "answer": "Haro, Spain"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Africa`s oldest continuous democracy?",
        "answer": "Botswana"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which European city`s harbor is called the Golden Horn?",
        "answer": "Istanbul`s"
    },
    {
        "question": "What state is home to a lake known as `America`s Dead Sea`?",
        "answer": "Utah"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which state boasts the world`s largest flat-top mountain?",
        "answer": "Colorado"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the only US state with four consecutive consonants uninterrupted by spaces?",
        "answer": "New Hampshire"
    },
    {
        "question": "What Mexican ciudad sits across the Rio Grande from El Paso, Texas?",
        "answer": "Ciudad Juarez"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which European country replaced the Escudo with the Euro?",
        "answer": "Portugal"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which European country replaced the Deutsche mark with the Euro?",
        "answer": "Germany"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which European country replaced the Drachma with the Euro?",
        "answer": "Greece"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which European country replaced the Pound with the Euro?",
        "answer": "Ireland"
    },
    {
        "question": "Saipan is the capital of which country?",
        "answer": "Northern Mariana Islands"
    },
    {
        "question": "Tunis is the capital of which country?",
        "answer": "Tunisia"
    },
    {
        "question": "What country shares a land border with Papua New Guinea to the west?",
        "answer": "Indonesia"
    },
    {
        "question": "What country are you most likely to hear its residents speak Malagasy?",
        "answer": "Madagascar"
    },
    {
        "question": "Malagasy is the native language of which country?",
        "answer": "Madagascar"
    },
    {
        "question": "Malagasy is the native language of which African country?",
        "answer": "Madagascar"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which European country is Tokaj wine produced?",
        "answer": "Hungary"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which country would you find the Tokaj wine region?",
        "answer": "Hungary"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Red River flows into what river?",
        "answer": "Mississippi River"
    },
    {
        "question": "What historic theater district is located in New York?",
        "answer": "Broadway"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which eastern US state is home to the Kittatinny Mountains?",
        "answer": "New Jersey"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Montana?",
        "answer": "Helena"
    },
    {
        "question": "The city of St. Louis is located in which state?",
        "answer": "Missouri"
    },
    {
        "question": "The port city of Sandusky is located in which state?",
        "answer": "Ohio"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which mountain range separates Europe from Asia?",
        "answer": "The Ural Mountains"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is the `Top of Europe`?",
        "answer": "Jungfraujoch, Switzerland"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which island was home to the Lighthouse of Alexandria?",
        "answer": "Pharos, Egypt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does a flower worn behind a woman`s right ear mean in Hawaii?",
        "answer": "She`s single"
    },
    {
        "question": "What strait separates Australia`s mainland from Tasmania?",
        "answer": "Bass Strait"
    },
    {
        "question": "What Pacific island chain is named for Philip IV`s Austrian queen?",
        "answer": "The Marianas"
    },
    {
        "question": "What name is shared by the rivers that run through Denison, Texas and Hanoi, Vietnam?",
        "answer": "Red River"
    },
    {
        "question": "What European nation still pledges its allegiance to a foreign monarch in its national anthem?",
        "answer": "The Netherlands"
    },
    {
        "question": "What city`s name means `steamy bay` thanks to geothermal activity?",
        "answer": "Reykjav\u00edk -- The name of Iceland`s capital Reykjav\u00edk translates literally to `steamy bay` or `smoky bay` in Old Norse."
    },
    {
        "question": "In what US state would you find Fort Point?",
        "answer": "California"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what US state would you find Fort Sill?",
        "answer": "Oklahoma"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what US state would you find Fort Donelson?",
        "answer": "Tennessee"
    }
]